time ever
working in Costa Rica. Uh, build my
first ever casino
pencil.
Man, this is a different world down here
for real.
You have to start by picking your own
lumber.
This is a piece of hard cedar I got
picked out. And uh, I don't know if you
can tell by looking at it, ain't nothing
straight in this guy. Nothing at all.
But what I'm going to do is come over
here. I'm finishing off a headboard
right here built in. I got my stuff
mitered all the way around and I'm
putting a cedar pattern in there. But
it's really really hard because you got
to start out by making this line
straight or it's never going to line up.
And uh
the only thing straight in this whole
place is my Johnson.
Got to get it.
I don't give a Not starting that
well.
Look at that on a young tail.
Look at this.
All the way down the line. Nowhere near
about a half inch off. So, I'm going to
have to damn keep that going like this.
Once I get one straight line, then I get
to rip down the other side and make
another straight line. It's absolutely
fantastic.
Man, am I on my line? There it is.
Real tricky.
Now, I suppose like I could break down
and go to Home Depot or Lowe's. They
they don't have a Lowe's here, but there
are supply houses in the in the gringo
towns. But I kind of came here to do
this. Like I wanted to learn how to do
stuff out of, you know, rough cut. You
know, most people be using a table saw
and, you know, a miter saw, radial arm
saw, all kind of man. I'm using a
batterypowered skill saw. That's it.
And you really got to spin it around
first.
You don't ever want to take and leave
your fat side long.
Should be trying to cut it like this.
Your damn saw be falling off the edge
like that. So I always turn it turn the
fat side up. Set the depth. That way I'm
not eating all the way through my saw
horses.
Y'all hear the howler monkeys?
Yeah, that's how monkeys. Hey, Thomas, I
sent you a text this morning, dog. Did
you do you hear the monkeys?
They're real close, man. Those are
howler monkeys, dude. They're fantastic.
Anyway,
let me get back to doing what I was
doing.
Heat.
All right,
that's one But now I need to set them in
half.
That's always fun. There be trying to
cut some Look at this.
That right there is left over. There's a
chickity chunk junked out of that guy.
Well, them howler monkeys ain't playing.
Uh, if y'all want, sell me. I'll show
you what I've already built thus far.
what I'm building now
or that little jungle where the damn
monkeys are
chisel it off just a little bit.
[applause]
[clears throat]
Just a little bit.
A little bit more.
Go dogs.
That's what it sounds like. Hey, them
howler monkeys literally sound like
people going to go dogs. I promise you
it does.
[snorts]
Now
that's the side I'm going to be using.
mark my 7 and 12.
I always come out three or four inches
cuz you know sometimes you get a little
dog uh doggy or something on uh on your
drop cut when you first come in.
Man, I'm telling y'all. Y'all don't hear
Do y'all hear them howler monkeys?
Somebody tell me yes. Jesus Christ.
They sound pissed.
Put in my level.
Oh, what's up, John Hall? How you doing,
man? Um, all right. Seven and a half.
Golly,
boy, this stuff is so red. You can't you
can't see the marks. I mean, I wish I
could show you. It is so damn red that
There's nothing easy about anything I'm
doing here. Uh, and if y'all are
carpenters and you have some tips for
me, you tell me. I'm pretty fair
carpenter.
I'm a carpenter. I'm not a carpenter. I
don't even know what a carpenter is.
Worked with a carpenter. I'm a
carpenter. Big difference.
Now, it's a special breed of human. They
can build anything out of a tree trunk.
We do things like, you know, fit 60-in
steel tubs in the twodoor Honda Civic
cuz I got to get work on time. We all
know what that's like.
John Hall Nico. Hey guys. Yeah, man. and
I uh I never really came live on uh
YouTube, but I do a lot of DIY stuff.
And most of y'all know me as a solar guy
and a video maker, but uh I've only done
those for like 3 years. I touched a
solar panel and a cell phone and a
social media at the same time in like
July of 22. Uh TV, just a redneck with
an iPhone now. Um I've been a carpenter
for 20 years and uh I know a little bit
more about that. What's up KC? All you
people, I've seen your names before. Now
I actually get to talk to you. Hello.
Huh? What's up?
Hold on. I'm going to show you this real
quick just so y'all know. Now look, this
is the line I'm tasked with following
running all over this type of wood.
Like can How'd you like to have to
follow that?
I mean, it's pretty tough. Anyways, and
here's what I'm building.
So, that light's terrible. This is my
headboard right here. Let's see if I can
clean that up. This is my headboard
right here. And this is all tongue and
groove Laurel. Uh, I had to rip a back
band down on this to seat it over and
get a nice clean line. And then I cut
all this cedar. And I mean, I handpicked
these pieces right here. Uh cuz look how
fire they are. [snorts]
Wish you could smell it. Um I built
this. This took forever. I hand beveled
all of those. That's cedar. Um and I I
built a little bench seat out of teak.
Very sturdy. And just to save lumber, I
used the drops and then I 45d them.
Everything is beveled. Um had a lot of
fun here as you can see. Um, but no
water can ever leak in here. I was
really worried about the siding leaking
cuz it's on this little pitch. So, so I
cut a 2 by6 to put a little angle on it.
That way when you sat here, you could
recline. But I was worried about the
pitch. You know, if they were just
butted up, water could leak in. So, and
then I woo rough cut cedar. I beveled
all of my joints.
It's that way water can never get in
here. And I have nothing behind them.
These are just nailed into each other.
Um,
look, you see? But if you take and hit
this thing, bro, it ain't moving. It
ain't moving. Um, and then there's no
nails in any of this. That's just
friction. Cut so tight. It will not
move. And I made my lattice. Uh,
[clears throat] and I had to frame all
this. Um, rabbited all my jams. Um, and
yeah, we got we got a lot to do, but uh
this is what I'm doing now, guys.
So, hit the wrong button. Excuse my live
streaming abilities. I am not a social
media creator. Uh, I've been unleashed
into the digital realm. They let me
loose. They never should have done that,
but now they can't get me out.
[snorts]
Can't see my line.
Where did he go? Now you see, you got to
stop. Why? Well, because if I mess this
line up, I have
I have screwed the pooch entirely. There
is no oops. You've messed up the entire
piece of wood.
[cough]
And if you got to get a new piece of
wood, all you got to do is go find a
tree out in the jungle, go out there,
cut it down, mill it with a chainsaw in
the jungle, then transport it back wet
and crib it up to dry, and wait like two
months. Yeah. Measure twice. Measure
what you measure repeatedly and cut once
here. I'm here to tell you, bro, the
consequences are serious. Very serious.
Heat. Heat.
Oh, wow. And you find out you didn't set
your guide deep enough or it moved. This
one's a little thicker than the other
one.
Is it? Is it, bro? Uh, yeah. And I've
been caught waking up at night hacking
up sawdust. I mean, it's terrible. John
Cold Augusta, yeah, you should come to
Costa Rica. It's wonderful here. I
haven't worn a shirt in over a week. One
time I left my shoes when I went to town
and was the white guy walking around
Dupala barefoot.
Heat. Heat.
So that's the pain I be talking about.
Look at this.
That's the same piece of wood,
but this side is about an eighth of an
inch thicker. And you can see it.
I'll mark it for you so you can see what
I'm talking about, man.
It's kind of nuts. It's really nuts. So,
my my song went through it one time. It
wouldn't go through it on the other
time.
Ah, man.
New Zealand. Are you the one who uh
emailed me? Somebody from New Zealand
emailed me. And guys, if you want to get
me to go somewhere, here's the deal.
Investment. I happen to be the one who
started them and like kind of, you know,
like signed them and stuff, but I have
to have a business reason to travel
somewhere. That way it justifies all my
expenses for the government. Um, so
yeah, I'll travel anywhere. I just need
to have a reason to go there, like
enough money to cover a plane ticket,
place to stay, floor to sleep on. um
something like that. And uh that's
basically it, man. I'd love to come to
New Zealand. Never been.
All right.
Okay.
Now, the
Yeah. All right. So, I got to measure it
here and find out. Boy, that light is
just brutal, guys. I'm sorry. I don't
know any other way to do it. I got to
measure this right here.
Come out. So, that's 21 and a quarter.
Well, yes, 21 and a quarter, but I need
to cut it like 22 so I can check it. In
fact, I want y'all to see how much
this is.
All right, I'mma cut 122 real quick.
All right.
Notice I had to square off this end
already
cuz if you don't square it off and and
you squared it off to what what your
square says it's not the same.
H darn it.
Hello.
Go
back.
Now,
excuse me, the flies.
So, we're back here.
This is the bane of my existence.
Oh, I like that.
Yeah, it looks good, doesn't it? Well,
see, look.
See, I got to take this. Can they see? I
got to take this and square it in there
like that. Now, that's a really good
tight joint. There's a little weeble up
here. I'm going to have to leave it
because I can't get everything out.
They just said, "How's the wood drying?"
Uh, so this cedar is still a little wet.
I use cedar out there at my sea shack in
Washington. And I mean, we just milled
it and I took it straight to the house.
The tree's been down for a while, but
what I'm going to Hold on. Do I need
Do I need to try and cut that out or No.
Yes.
Hold on. What? It's a little
See, that's the thing. It looks like a
little little weeble wobble right now.
Let me go ahead and get this one cut.
Is this you, too?
God damn it.
So, you got to hold it out here. The
more you push it in, you got to square
it there. Make sure that's nice and
tightish.
And you got to mark it here
and mark it there.
Take your square and just throw it in
the trash. You hear me? Just throw your
square in the trash. Doesn't matter. You
will not be squaring nothing. What
you'll be doing is marking every piece.
I've also found that unless you unless
you putting in a door or a tub or
something, you really don't need a
level.
You don't. It just matters what unless
somebody comes in there with a level,
you'll never ever ever know uh if it's
level or not. So, I've been using my
eyeball. What? Get
I needed you for a sentence.
Uh what sentence?
For a voice over.
Oh, okay. Come here. What do you need?
So, this is what my life is like. A lot
of times we do things. Huh. No, I'm not
building with zero fasteners. No, I have
a nail gun. I have I'm working on it.
That would be a fun project.
Which one? That one. Which one is it? Is
it that one right there? What was
my mark? Was that the mark? Which one
was my mark?
Which way was I holding it?
Don't know.
So that was it. If I was Mark said that
would be it there. Okay.
YouTube.
Mhm. Yeah. So, like what I did is I just
pulled up my phone a couple days ago,
like yesterday, and I was like, "Hey, I
never live stream on YouTube ever, but I
do more YouTube than anything
else." Uh, do do y'all want me to cut on
live? And and like I think it was 160
people said, "Yeah." So, I was like,
"Okay, that's a that's a fair amount of
yeses. I cut it on." And
these are the people we should be hyping
up the docu series, too. Well, well, you
want to tell them what you're doing,
kid? Can
Oh, yeah. So, I'm actually working on
the first The first one's almost done.
It will probably come out in a few days.
What is it?
I'm about to say that. I didn't know.
We're We're filming a document series
called Building Reality. And it's it's
kind of a take on how the normal reality
shows aren't reality. They're they're
fake. They're not reality. So, it's it's
a very up close thing of his thoughts
and like what goes on behind the scenes
other than the like minute 30 seconds
you see on social media to like make
these houses and these things and
the whole process.
Y'all see what we're doing now, but what
you don't see is the thought process to
get here. Like people always like,
"Yeah, we're building a cassita." Yes,
but why are we building a cassita right
here? What is this place? You might not
know that the the city I'm in is a
renewable energy center of this country.
Um, you know, the thought, why am I
using traditional building materials?
Where did these come from? Who got the
money for this lumber? Tikos, man. I'm
doing everything with thought and
intention because that is the business.
That is the branding. However you cut
it, um, that's what you'll get down to,
man. And I, uh, I think that
Well, would y'all like to see how this
actually works?
Yes, y'all need to let me know. I think
I emailed you back, Kai. Would y'all
like to see like a a you know fulllength
series on how we got here, what we do
here, what it's actually like? Or do you
just want to see the same we're
putting on the internet
now? Things like that,
cutting stain grade with a skill saw off
your leg and leaving the line perfectly,
that's just normal here. Like that's
that's average. That's average. Oh, the
old Bible. Uh send me an email
failsmedroup@gmail.com,
please. And old Bible people,
we have lots of Bible stuff to do. Just
not right this second.
Now, is that passful to you? You see,
see that little
Yeah.
Now, the other thing is I can try and
whittle, but I think I'll make it
worseer. And cuz this is cedar, this is
going to keep drying a little bit over
time.
But wait, do you Oh,
[screaming]
now
you get me another rack of nails, kid.
2in nails.
Now that's
that's one. Now I got a few more. And
wait, do you see? I'm gonna put a design
on this. Where's uh my campfer? Before I
show y'all, does anybody know what a
campfer is? Does anybody know what a
campfer is? Huh?
A camper?
Anybody?
I gots to know before I show you.
No, no, nobody knows what a campfer is.
Nobody at all. All right.
This is a campfer. A camper is what's
left over after you rip a bevel off of
something. And most people just keep
them as drops or something, man. Burn
them. After I take this, I'm going to
put an X on that
from corner to corner. I'm going to have
to bevel it right here. But I think
that's going to be harder than a box of
nails. Who agrees?
Have I ever heard of water electrolysis?
Yes, I had.
[snorts] No. No. No. Yeah. Yes, I know
about water electrolysis. The problem
with it, Julie and I talked about it at
Nauseium. Fact, Julian's going to be
here in about a week or so to visit me.
Um, but
the problem with electrolysis is it
takes far more energy to to actually
pull the hydrogen out than you're going
to make. Now, this makes sense. Uh, if
your batteries are full, water's coming
down from the sky or the sun's shining
and you have an excess of energy. Yes,
you could use electrolysis to extract
the hydrogen and then store it for later
use when you needed it. But the problem
is you can't store the hydrogen.
It seeps through the milk tanks.
So, like I move through things pretty
quickly and what I know verifiably is
that all energy comes from planet Earth.
We just repatriate it and use it how we
see fit. And I think I can take it
straight out of the dirt because
that's where it comes from. You just
have to think differently than other
people to understand that. And I did not
feel comfortable doing any of these
types of things in America for obvious
reasons. So now I'm here in the jungle
building a number of things. And when I
get done with these, I'm going to build
the energy center. After I get the solar
and the hydro and all the stuff that we
all know about done, then I'm going to
play a little bit. Uh, I got some ideas.
The owner of Big Battery, Eric Lungren,
he's going to be here. He's flying in on
this week, the end of this week. Uh,
he's going to come meet me. We're going
to talk about what we're going to do
here. And so, yeah, that's what I got
going on. I'm going to stop talking and
start working again.
Look right here.
Hold it. Boy, this is man too,
guys.
Oh, man. Hold it.
Mark it. [clears throat]
Oh,
man.
I always come through and scribe it on
the front because that's the side I'm
seeing. I don't ever know what the
bottom cut looks like.
Square it off and then cut that guy.
Bing bing.
What?
Email sent. Awesome, Dan. We staying
after it.
Who thinks my life looks like fun? Do
you think it's a lot of fun?
Love to know what y'all think.
Oh, that that's
that's that guy. That's that guy that
fits so tight. You got to get his ass in
there.
That's what I'm talking about. See
that? There we go. Bing bing. Now that
is the best piece of the day.
And I have been super
concerned with making sure everything is
super tight.
And then I realized that this wood is
going to slowly shrink over a period of
weeks and months.
Big worm CR.
Okay, Kyle. Trying to answer as best I
can. You need some Do you need a a
thing?
cuz I'm close close to getting this
thing.
See, like three or four more pieces.
Now, if you think my life is a lot of
fun, it it can be sometimes, but usually
I'll be working too much to enjoy
anything. Oh,
now most people always think that they
trying to accomplish something or get
where they want to in life.
Boy, not quite like that. Damn. You
can't see it, but this one's got a damn
gap in order to be flush to the top. See
if I go this way. Got to be any better.
Way better. Way better. Okay.
Mark there.
God damn it.
Marking something with your left hand is
the most up thing in all
construction. Can I get an amen?
[clears throat]
I take.
Well, if you're a weird-handed
left-handed person, that's okay.
Boy, that was tough. Ola,
square it off.
up, man.
Let's see what we got.
Now, most people would cut all this with
a damn miter saw, and I would have for a
lot of years, but 3 years ago when I
moved into the van, I started just using
the tools I could take with me, which
was a skill saw, a drill, some DeWalt
Uh, and I've been through
Hurricane Helen, building castles,
fixing my van on the side of the road,
installing all across America with
just these tools. And I've gotten pretty
proficient with just them.
And that is gorgeous.
about that.
Or is it that one?
No,
I like the other side.
Well, I cut it for that way though.
But that's gross.
Well,
I see
the joints aren't good.
You got to have tight fat joints, you
know.
You see, I can do that now. All right.
Which do you like? Do you like this side
out with bigger gaps
or do you want See, cuz it's cut the
other way.
Little gaps. Okay. Or
do we want the tight cuts with the See
the nice pretty cuts?
No.
What do y'all want? Huh? What do we
want? All right. What do we think? Do we
listen to Charlie?
Yeah.
Well, that would make you happy if I
started listening to you more, wouldn't
it, kid?
[screaming]
everything.
All right, two more pieces. Oh, maybe
two in a piece.
All right, so we want
this side out here.
No,
that side's prettier or you want that
side out. All right.
Square it right here. That side's nice
and tight. And that's nice and tight. So
then
Oh, Mark the bottom.
Bane of my existence. You know, for a
short person to have to bend down, it's
it's a tough thing.
I saw this kick himself in the
head the other day.
That's impressive. I if I could kick
myself in the head, I'd be a
gazillionaire.
I'd go kick myself in the head in famous
places all over the world. [laughter]
Is there like a yogi master? I need a
yogi tai chi master to teach me to kick
myself in the head.
His leg was cuz his leg's short like
that. So it was like straight out.
That's the length it was from his leg to
kick his forehead.
I know of one way I could smash myself
in the head with a leg, but not like
that. [laughter]
Oh man. Yeah, wrestling.
I'd have been great at it. I'd I really
I really would have.
You probably
I would I'd be a great wrestler.
Look at me. I'm jacked for you
know. cyborg. Okay.
All right.
I don't know why I was being
temperamental, but
ancient Gnostic Christians, uh, yes,
I've studied the Bible my entire life.
That's why I'm covered in like Jesus
tattoos and Greek and uh you know I
translated I taught myself Greek when I
was in prison using a college Greek one
textbook and translated two of the
gospels from Greek into English. It was
Matthew and Mark.
Now there it is. Now look, we have a
problem. That one's a little bit thicker
than the other one.
Why did you do that one?
Huh?
Why did you do that side?
Okay.
On that side
it
no. All right.
I can't.
Now, I will admit I'm trying to find a
dowel maker. I need something to cut the
dowels because I could dial everything
really easy. Not on this one. This is a
build that the the local Tikos framed up
while I was on. They did all the metal
studs. Um they did the concrete. They
did all that. I had them rough it in so
I could come finish it out. Um so
yeah, I have a
They said, "Have you done drugs or do
you do drugs?"
Look,
sometimes you say no to drugs, but they
don't listen. And you need to understand
that it's okay. Give yourself a break.
Bing
later. [laughter]
So I uh what's it called?
No, I uh I don't do drug when I was a
younger man. You know, when I was a
younger man, I know I don't look like
it, but I used to be a little wild back
in the day. Now I'm pretty normal. Um
Hey, hand me that drop right there. Both
them drops. Them cedar drops. Those are
the last couple pieces I need, I think.
Yep.
You want to hurry up?
I'm trying to. I got to finish this bed
and I'll get that
f. [laughter]
Yeah. Well, hey,
what a coincidence.
Hold on.
There's a whole jungle of plants out
there. There's more psychoactive stuff
in this rainforest than than than
anywhere else on planet Earth, man.
Like, it's everywhere. And I'm here to
learn about all of it, man. Um, you know
how they kill a rats here, which we have
a rat problem right now. Uh, they told
me they catch one of the toads, a safo,
and they kill the toad and they boil it
in water and then cook rice with the
water, and then put the rice out, just
dump it on the ground, you come back the
next day, there'll be dead rats
everywhere. We have rats now. They're
rats. And uh I don't want to kill a
toad, but I got to find out the the real
deal on like killing toads with a rat or
killing rats with a toad. I guess you'd
kill a rat and a toad at the same time,
but you know what I have said. So
look. All right. So now look, I got to
take this.
I still need your sentence, but
I will. Give me one minute. I got to
finish it. Look, I got Charlie wants me
to go record something for something.
But don't y'all think I should finish
this bed and let y'all see it before I
do that?
It's one sentence, but I can't I can't
let the public here yet. It's not It's
not public media yet.
[laughter]
Hey, Big Worm. Hey, look here, bro. I'm
telling you, I don't like her. That girl
lies, man. You can't trust no white girl
like that, bro. Bro, you got to get you
a dirty footed one.
Mm- Nope.
What are we talking about?
You can't do it like that. Oh, I got
Hold on. I got some more already cut. I
don't have to rip. Hold on. Look, I
forgot. This pissed me off so bad. So
bad. I spent all this time. I handpicked
this one piece. Look how gorgeous this
piece was. I went ahead and ripped it. I
cut the first one off and it went bing
and split.
I was so pissed.
South Carolina MMA news. Hey, I'm a huge
MMA fan. Um, I have a picture of uh me
with Julian Brown and Malcolm Wellmakers
coach. I literally used to spar with
Malcolm uh two winners ago in Augusta at
Fagler's MMA. And yeah, dude, I love it.
I'm going to be bringing coaches down
here to to train us when I get
everything set up. Groups come down
here. I want to have everybody here who
knows how to run, fight, build, like
reality. That's why it's called reality.
If you want to exist in the real world
before they made all these rules and
warning labels, bro, you had to be able
to build your own house, get your own
food, fight, run, survive. You had to be
smart, intelligent, and those types of
people really don't exist anymore.
They're very rare. Um, I strive to be
one, but uh that's what it is here.
Welcome to reality.
Population us.
How old? How old do y'all think I am?
Hold on. Hey, Kobe. Let me
Yeah.
Give me one second. Let I got to look.
Because right where your head is, I got
to mark this
with this side out. Right. We want that
that pretty side out. Correct.
There you go.
The 51 is crazy.
How old do y'all think I am? 51.
Boy, that's rough. 51.
51. 35. [clears throat]
51. [laughter]
Who the said 51? That's painful,
wasn't it?
Someone said 35,
43, 45, 44, 19,
40,
24, and 51 at the same time.
I am 5'4.
I can't I'll be I can't get kicked off
live the first time.
Hey, go grab that pencil for me. That
red one right there. right there.
Um, now I am 39 years old.
Are we going to go see Wilbert?
Yeah, we're gonna That's
Mom said you're going.
Yes.
Can I go?
Huh?
Yeah. Yeah. If y'all want to come. We're
going to go have like dinner and like
we're going to go We're going to go to
town and go to the store. You know when
you when you go to town in Costa Rica,
that's it. It's the whole day. If you
got to leave, you think stopping to go
to Lowe's is bad, bro. You have no idea.
Okay, case in point. I had to buy a weed
eater. Okay, so I I went to go buy a
weed eater and they were like, "Does it
work?" Oh, yeah. Here you go. They
poured some Coke in it. It It looked
like Coca-Cola. I swear to God. It did.
They put It might have been mixed in
Coke bottle. There was only a little
bit. They poured it in there and crunk
it up. And And so I said, "Okay." And I
tried it and it it wouldn't release.
It'd start, but it wouldn't stop. And I
was like, "Oh." And they were like, "Oh,
okay.
uh we'll take it to the repair shop and
they threw it in the truck like right
there. They're like, "Okay, my lawyer,
Alex, the dude that owns the pawn shop,
got in there, drug and we drove it to
the 10 repair shop." He goes in, drops
it off, comes back out 10 minutes later.
He's like, "You can pick it up tomorrow.
Same price. We pay for this." [laughter]
So like, and then you go to the hardware
store, you have to tell them what you
want. And it's not like Lowe's. Screws
come by the one. You have to tell them
how many screws you want.
The time that checking out Thanks.
Oh god. You to check out, dude. Oh my
god. If you come here, be prepared to
slow down whether you want to or not.
Um,
that's probably why I'm like I am cuz
I'm trying to move at America's speed in
Costa Rica. Um, and there's something
called a Tiko hour here. Do you know
what a Tiko hour is? Somebody tell me.
Tico time. Hold on while
Tico time. Oh man.
So Tiko time.
Is that a good fit there or not?
Holy balls. That's terrible.
Huh?
So, I'm touching that.
See, that's what that bird ate. No bugs.
Those little berries.
Joe has tattoos and no muscles.
Incorrect. They're prison tattoos and I
have small and efficient muscles.
Running results in Ultra Magazine and
see the 50 mileers and 40 mileers I've
won. Show up and work out with me, big
dog. I'll smoke show your ass, too.
Like, in a real sense, and laugh at you
when you're out of breath. Promise, bet.
But, but welcome it. I want you to come
teach me. It's fun for me.
Hey, Charlie. How many people have you
seen get just drug?
Oh, there there's a large a large
number. [laughter] Push-ups immediately
after runs. There's no break.
Run in the hills.
Right into it.
It's hilarious.
Oh, we all run up the hill with Joe
before.
Oh, no. Nah. Hey, you don't have to be
jacked up to go. But when you wanted
three white boys on a 90man, get there,
dog. I promise you. Quick,
you're gonna get swole for parole, dude.
Quick, fast, in a hurry.
Or do I need to flip that around? Is
that the problem? Do you like the worm?
Um.
Ah.
Is that [clears throat]
See, something's up in that cut.
I can't I can't tell.
So, that's it. I need to come down. All
right. A little bit more. You can't just
cut one, man. You can't square it.
Nothing in here is straight. The only
straight line is the one that you make.
And it is really a pain in the ass, if
I'm honest.
Cut, recut, shim, reshim,
All right.
See how that does.
There's that piece I'm working on right
there.
See? Lock.
Pretty much locked in here.
[clears throat]
Boy,
I ain't got no muscles, but I can pull a
piece of wood up with one hand
and mark that from the underside.
I can tell you that much. Woo! That some
is strong, too.
[clears throat]
God dog. Yeah, that sucks. That really,
really sucks.
God damn almighty.
line. Three more pieces.
Helpers are gone. Yeah, helpers are
gone, dude. Um I just Nah, I got rid of
them. They weren't working, man. And
they slowed me down, like literally. And
they they just came here. They they
wanted a free trip to Costa Rica and
they wanted to meet somebody they
think's famous and that was about it,
bro.
You know, that's my problem is I'm not a
social media person. I'm I'm just out
here doing it and showing y'all. That's
my life. And so when the fake people
show up, we do not get along. It's very
evident very quickly.
had a number of other people reach out
wanting to come up here. And you know,
I'm just looking for people that that
are fun to hang out with. [laughter]
Like, you see this? If y'all were here
with me, you'd be nailing this in,
too. Like, I just want people to hang
out. Like, and if there's more people
here, I ain't got to work nearly as much
and we can go to the river. There's a
river right across the street with
Native American artifacts right there on
the bank. Um, it's a lovely place.
Beach about an hour and a half away.
Airbnbs under $60 out the Woo all over
this country. Um, just a fantastic place
in my opinion if you like getting away.
Now, if you want like a Dave and Busters
and like that,
you and I don't have anything in common,
but also just just probably not for you.
Probably not for you. None of the places
I go is for you at all. Tell you that
much with a legitimate fact.
Two more.
Make it [snorts] easy. I'mma mark it.
A lot easier if you mark it on the
ground first.
[snorts]
A lot easier to see. That lines up
pretty well.
Because most people think this is some
like entrepreneur doing something
special in a foreign country, but what
it's really like is one of your
degenerate friends won the lottery and
bought a place in Costa Rica and is now
up there just doing what the he
wants to. He's got a badass girlfriend.
They got some kids. They like to work
out, do crazy Um, live a Spartan
lifestyle.
There's no fried foods. They work out
every day. you know, high emphasis on
personal responsibility and
self-improvement.
Um, but yeah, other than that, it's kind
of like David Gogggins, HGTV, and Jack
Ash blended together.
All of those shows are wonderful, but I
must point out that if you went there,
like you like like to watch David
Gogggins, but you wouldn't want to run
with him. And you might like Crocodile
Hunter, but you ain't hopping on no damn
alligator. And everything you see me
doing is much the same. You'd probably
love to watch it, but if you came and
did it, you'd find out that it's not
exactly fun and comfortable and
enjoyable. It's a lot of work.
Now let's see
down here
pretty well.
Where's my marks?
My marks.
I'm actually gonna cut this one a little
shy. Why am I going to cut this one a
little short down here? All right, you
see this? I'm marking this piece and
I'mma cut it a little shy. Do you know
why?
Anybody tell me why I want to cut that
guy short?
Solar, no problem.
Yeah, I'm with you, Jason. I'm with you.
Mhm.
Oh, yeah. Dude, [laughter]
you want to know about Costa Rica? I
just recorded the video telling people.
I've had so many people reach out. Look,
if you ever thinking of moving
somewhere, show up there. Just go.
That's how I go everywhere. I don't book
an itinerary. I don't book anything. I
literally just travel somewhere and with
a backpack and get on Airbnb. I might do
a little planning beforehand, like make
a contact, but just go and you'll find
out everything you need to know first
and foremost if you want to live there.
And second, you'll find local people who
will give you the real deal because
everything on the internet is just
trying to take your money, sell you an
idea of something to take your money.
There's very real free information out
there. Uh, I try and give you as much as
I can, but there ain't much and you need
to understand that.
So,
oh man, I need a straight actual
straight edge. Kobe, hand me that level,
kid.
That yellow one.
180 grand.
I I haven't told anybody how much I paid
for this place yet, but it was the magic
number. Um,
you know, I
I can't tell you quite everything, but I
can tell you I am in the Ala province.
I'm up in the mountains, uh, about 2
hours from, uh, the Nicaraguan, well,
hour and a half from the Nicaraguan
border. And I am uh
I like it here.
But I'm
When you buy something here, you just
got to have a When you buy anything, you
got to have a lick of sense. Cuz you
think you're buying a house, what you're
really doing is is tying yourself to a
piece of property forever until you sell
it. You got to take care of it.
And before you buy something, like I
asked you, why are you buying something?
Like why would you buy this piece of
property?
Yeah.
Um, [clears throat]
you have a good answer as to why, then
you can kind of figure out some of the
other parts.
Can I make this?
Tell me if this passes OSHA guidelines.
Heat.
See my line?
Left it all the way down. Probably not
the safest, but it works.
So, we're going one last piece here.
Trying to move this so y'all can see.
Pass.
Nah, I'm not going to get a table saw.
That's the whole thing. I want to do it
without it.
Anybody can cut wood park with a table
saw, big dog. But look at that skill
saw.
That's the whole reason of this.
I want to be able to do stuff without
using all the That's why I'm here.
I can build anything, bro. Been doing it
my whole life. Most recently, I built an
app to run all my construction remotely.
And
man,
you know, I'm trying to figure out how
to do a primal. I was born in Papa New
Guinea. Uh, and the people in Papa New
Guinea going to the forest with nothing.
Nothing. They make their clothes, their
tools, their house, and their food. And
I ask you, who is more intelligent?
Those primitives who can't read or write
or me with my science and math and apps
and digital.
That's what I'm trying to get to. True
knowledge.
True knowledge.
All right. One more. One more drop. All
right, I got one more piece, guys. One
more piece. We riding together. One hour
in.
How about this one?
Last piece right there. Yeah, you see
it? It's
right.
So, I'm leaving a little space at the
bottom on all these so it doesn't have
direct ground contact.
First, you got to make sure that it fits
real well.
Is that a tight joint? That's a real
tight joint.
That one.
That
right. Cut it first.
Go.
You see how you use that ladder to keep
that wood from moving?
Mhm.
Don't need a saw bench, do you?
Uh,
not really.
Just a lick of sense.
Yeah.
Well, having a lick having a lick of
sense is the most useful thing on planet
Earth.
Problem
it is. Most people are born with it and
school like works it out of you. You're
taught that you must learn things from
book
outside and put your hands on something.
You'll learn the purpose of all that
they're trying to teach you.
Look at that heart pine. I mean cedar.
God, I wish you could smell it.
It does smell crazy.
Oh. All right.
Wood.
That's it
right there.
And then
I'm just going to measure that. Come off
quarter inch.
So
6 and 38
6 and 3/4
6 and 3/4 6 and 5/8. So it's a half inch
out.
6 and 3/4 6 and 5/8.
We're just going to cut over him. Get
that cut. Which side do I want out? I
like that one. So, that's going to be 6
and 3/4. 6 and 5/8. I'm going to take a
quarter off. That's going to be 6 and
38.
No, I need to square that first,
though.
I hate this.
Which is plum? Which one's your control
line?
Oh man.
I'm going to cut it exact and then I can
always rip it off if I need to.
That's terrible. That's a horrible pot.
Is it 6 and 3/4 or 6 and 5/8 would
right?
6 and 5/8.
Six and 3/4
8 inch difference.
Let's see.
Yeah.
Little level. This looks real
professional, doesn't it?
Be honest. If you hired something to do
somebody to do something in your house
and showed up and they was working like
this,
what would you do?
Would you allow them to continue working
on your home or would you come to get
out of there?
That's hilarious.
Well, once again, line has been left.
And back to the whole skill table saw
thing. You see why I don't need a table
saw this? You'd have to damn get up,
walk all the way over there, set the
guide on there. I just mark that thing
right here and cut it. It's a whole lot
better system.
It's still a little
It's still a little tight. Too tight.
There's my cut. There it is.
That's how it's supposed to go.
Boy,
I'm talking about
just a just a smidge right there. And
that thing's going in. That is gorgeous.
It might even go in like this if I
square it up.
Ah. Ah, just a
That's a bl That is a blonde here.
That ain't even a brown one. Not even a
brunette. I'm talking about a tizzle of
a dizzle. That's the worstest thing to
have to have to cut out that much. Oh my
god.
Oh my god.
I kind of want to try and beat its ass
in there first. Should I try and beat it
in there or should I just trim it off?
No, man. School's behavioral control.
That's all it is, man. They fill your
head full of nonsense and so you never
take time to learn anything. Then after
you get out of school, especially if you
mess up and go to college, you've wasted
like all of your life. So you don't have
an option other than to do what they
taught you to do. That's how it's set up
to work.
I literally just got out of school and I
am now.
Yeah.
It is not going to teach you how to make
that kind of trim cut. Okay.
That was pretty that was tricky.
Tricky.
All right.
Now, where she fit?
Hey,
boy.
Nope. I mean,
you can put nails in it if you want to.
It don't matter. Does not matter. Look,
just for shits and giggles.
Bam.
Hot damn.
Hell yeah. Now the last part. I'll show
you what I have did.
Look. So now I got all this, got my
cedar in, and now I got to take this
camper and put an X on it. And I think
that'll just look bad as What do
y'all think? Huh?
Well,
I have framed some houses, but I ain't
an old guy. In fact, I'm always usually
the youngest person on the job site
every time. Um, like clockwork.
All right.
So, now move that ladder for me, kid.
No, you're all right.
Now trying to put this thing where that
light and just crushing them cuz it's
horrible. I hate live streaming when I'm
working. This sucks balls. I'm glad
you're enjoying it. All right.
So now
come here, kid.
Hold this right here.
I need you to hold this. Now look, you
see that line? That needs to be You see,
you want that lined up with that that
miter right there. Okay. So I'm going to
come down here and mark it on this end.
Now hold on. Now come up some. All
right. Bing.
How's that look?
I don't know what kind of angle that is,
but I'm going to guess. We're just going
to guess.
because I don't know. I don't have to
know the angle. I just have to make the
cut. Right. You following me? And I'm
going to check this. We're going to see
cuz it's just an eyeball.
I'm going have to cut that guy on the
back.
Yeah. So, I got that thing marked. Now,
let's see.
Can Cananan?
Nah, man. Dude, when I heard they closed
the woods in Canada, I was like, "Bro,
the humans think they own the woods."
[laughter]
This legit made me laugh. It's like
I know somewhere Jesus was like, "Hey,
uh uh Canada, you can't close the woods.
[laughter]
You can't tell people they can't go
outside. That's all there is. That's
planet. Y'all made the houses. You can
control those that you can't close the
woods." [laughter] It wrecked
me.
I still It's so funny to me. That's like
saying uh the the air is closed.
[laughter] You can't you can't do it. Oh
boy.
They Yeah, they said you couldn't go in
the woods.
[laughter]
here.
All right. So, that is a pretty good
noise kid. Come here. Hold that.
Hold this. Look. Come here. Hold this.
Square this. Flush this end up. You see?
Like that.
Right there with that edge. Make sure
that that's level right there. You see
how them edges are level?
Are still level?
It's um angles and stuff with the
here. Does it need to mark? Cuz that's
what you got to do is you got to hold it
and look.
Let me see.
Yeah.
Is that it? Let me see.
No, that's a that's okay. All right.
Yeah. Just hold that. Hold it right
there. Cuz I got to mark this. And this
has got to be pristine.
Two-way cut
the back.
it.
That's tough.
Hey, hold it back one more time cuz look
at this. Hey, how how do you mark this?
Like, how do you mark this?
Hold it back there.
Like, this is hell.
So, I'm trying to mark this right here.
You got it.
And I can't
can't get my pencil back there.
Let me see.
God, dog. All right.
Ah, like how thwarted by this stupidity.
I guess let me cut off this one first
and look at it again maybe.
But this is the finish. Like it's got to
be right. It's two little pieces. But
these cuts is fitting to be hell. Oh
yeah. How about 10 to 12 ribby?
Yeah. Hey, how [laughter]
threatening I wait. Hey guys, you see
it? You see they've convinced the entire
world that you live in their houses and
you're arguing about your ability to go
into the woods or not, your ability to
catch a fish out of the river,
your ability to kill an animal to feed
yourself and your family.
That's the point we're at on planet
Earth.
And people are actively like arguing
about your right to piss in a bathroom,
your right to have a baby or not, like
your right to marry a person. People are
literally arguing about this in the
billions. And I just had to leave. Like
that's the simulation. They've just con
convinced everybody that these things
exist. And I'm like, "Okay, while y'all
are arguing about that and the election
for the supreme ruler of Earth, I'm just
going to go over here to the jungle and
learn to eat out of the woods."
[laughter]
There you go. Have fun.
This is the most insane thing I've ever
witnessed.
Oh, that's Florida.
Well, I tell you, Florida
stupid. Well, Florida's not
The problem with Florida is that it's
soon going to be back underwater in my
opinion. You can tell when the insurance
companies begin pulling out of a place.
Um,
you can tell. Colobe, will you go back
there and hold that for me?
Is that in where it need to be?
There we go.
Right there. All right,
boy. Hey, we we we cut it two pieces
away from from this.
Hold on. Hold one more time. Let me go
one more time.
No. Well, look. Hey. Hey. Hey.
Is that where it need to be? Cuz that
mark is different. Make sure you got it.
Exact. Hey, that's that's a very
important job. You just don't know it.
Yes,
that's exactly where it was.
Okay. All right.
So now, boom.
Boom.
It's not lost on me that the time will
probably be here soon when you're going
to have to know a lot of these skills or
else you're not going to live. And so
I'm here trying to learn them now.
No, now.
All
right, kid.
Yeah.
Go. Well, when you're ready, go ahead
and hold that. I'm going nail this.
Watch this. You put that down like this.
This is going to be fire. I don't I feel
like that's going to snap.
You think this going to snap? Who think
this ain't going to snap when I'm in?
What? I promise you.
Now, so your end is right. Look,
remember what I told you? We work end to
end. We got to get that end set. So, we
got two points to work to. Right now,
where's that 6ft level? Go get that big
level
and we're going to make a straight line
out of it.
Yeah. Yeah. No, Florida. I
man, I find everything the same way that
Look, all these houses I have, I found
the badass Airbnbs I found by running a
ultramarathons in the tiny most obscure
little towns ever. You never would have
found these towns unless you went to run
this up race. Um, and that's what
I do. If when I land in a place like
Costa Rica, no itinerary. I show up with
a backpack and a two-eek trip and I just
go and I get away from anybody that
speaks English. I get away from tourist
towns. I find regular people living in
the street. That's what I'm looking for.
I talk to alcoholics and drunks and find
out about properties and do very
unadvisable things for most people. But
then again, I've spent my entire life
learning, training, running, fighting.
Um, I've been in the streets. I've lived
in a van. I've been in multi-million
dollar meetings. So, I've equipped
myself to live like this. If you want to
come find the real part of the real
world, you got to discover it, bro.
Ain't nobody You ain't going to find it
on no website. Did the real people still
living on planet Earth, uh,
traditionally in the way you want to
learn, you ain't going to find them
online. They don't know what Google is.
There's not an address, a street sign,
or mailbox in this entire country, bro.
And, uh, this is just going to be a
jumping off place for me to get to
somewhere even crazier. So, yeah, I
know. All right. Now, watch this kid.
So, if you put that in the end,
you'll see that that thing is
here. Hold that right there. Now, look.
The only place where there's a little
gap is right there. Now, look. Look
down. You can't see. See? See? It's
touching everywhere else. So, if it's
touching, we want to go ahead and nail
it. Why?
Cuz it'll stay there.
That's right. It'll stay there. And then
when we need to come down and move these
other parts,
they can move.
Correct. When I did that, it
locked it in pretty much
down.
Shoot it on the other side. Now, now
there you go. Now, shoot it straight in.
Don't Don't come up. Shoot it straight.
There you go. Better. Why am I shooting
it on the underside?
I don't know.
Hold on. Stand up. Why am I shooting it
on the other side?
So you won't see the nails.
I [laughter] died sneaking with
suspicion, but I didn't.
Hey, go grab another p one of these
campers. We got two one piece left.
Remember these drops I told y'all about?
Yeah.
Who's Grady Jud?
Grady Judosco
Grady Judoy.
Yeah. Who is Gford? Oh, Tampa. N Tampa.
Pulk County.
We got one more drop. This one will be a
little trickier cuz I'm going to have to
This drop right here. I'm going to have
to bring it and 45. I'm going to 45 it.
Well, let me guess. You took the time to
pick out a good one, didn't you?
A straight one. There you go.
This one's a little bend at the end.
That one's not I don't know. Let's see.
No, that one's not big enough. So, let's
go over
here and pick up a drop. So, it's not
wide enough, you know, but there's a ton
of them in here.
Now, this one feels like it's the same
thickness and width. Hold
that one because we might have to use
two different pieces cuz it all came off
of that.
That's another good one there. You see
the thickness? You can tell this side's
a little thin
and that one's is heavy. You can feel
it. So,
now
hell no. ain't jarring right now. I'm
working, bro. So, last thing
this way, get this damn light. That
light is horrible, guys. I'm sorry.
There we go. Now you can see what I'm
twerking with.
All right.
So, same thing, kid.
We got to start this. Look. Come here.
So, your job is going to be to try and
hold that steady right there. All right.
And let me work it as I need to because
what I'm going to do is get this marked
on this side.
Mark that on concrete first and then you
can mark. Are you where you need to be?
Yeah.
All right. Let me see.
You get this. I want you to go get your
mama so she can see this.
Last piece.
Go ahead. You got them cutting them. We
screw them off.
I got screw. Screwing them off. Screwing
them off. The easy part. It's kind of
like in painting, like paint putting the
paint on the wall is the easy part for
sure.
Hold on. I've just seen seen something.
That piece is a little wavy down there.
See? You see what I mean by different
sizes, kid?
Yeah.
Look, I could just tell by feeling them.
That one's a quarter inch thinner.
And none of these are exactly perfect.
True, either.
quart inch. Hey, come here.
I want you to hold that one down there.
No, no, look. Hold that one up there.
Sorry. I'm going to get this one marked
first cuz that one's a little wavy down
there. So,
I mean, you could use two,
but it's like
I know, but watch
here's the thing. I know. And you know,
there's going to be a bed in front of
this forever.
Yeah.
So, it doesn't
really
It doesn't really need to be, you know,
perfect down there. There's a little
something wavy.
Yeah.
You'll never see it.
And way do y'all see the bed I'm going
to make? I'm gonna make the entire
underside of my bed into a drawer
because I don't want to put a closet
anywhere in here. Closets are stupid. I
only have like four pairs of shorts. I
don't even wear a shirt anymore. So, you
really don't need a closet taking up
space. It's stupid.
I'm going to turn the entire underside
of my bed in. All right, kid. Come back
in.
There you go. Hold it down there.
And then I'm going make my mark
up here.
Got it.
Now, one more thing.
Put that on the top. We're going to have
to There's a little wave in
[clears throat] it down there, but I got
to make sure we run through before I
mark this.
right here. Okay, that's it.
No, no, don't don't move. Don't move.
Now, what angle is that cut?
I [snorts] don't know, but I'm
eyeballing it.
I cannot even tell. All right.
You can use your square
like just
homie. This is me guessing.
Yeah.
Just straight guessing. And what I'm
going to do is cut a little long.
That way
you can cut it off. You can never
correct. I cannot add I left my only
wood stretcher back back uh in America.
So if you mess it up
Yeah. wood stretcher.
That actually work.
Yeah. Yeah, if you if you cut a piece
too short, you got to have wood stretch
structure that you ain't going to get
back. It's how it works.
I had a blue one and a red one.
Every Anybody ever remember their first
day having to go get the wood stretcher?
Find time.
All right,
so [snorts] I need like this.
Come on. Please be right. Please be
right.
Okay, here we go.
There's my mark there, Kobe. Look,
I think that's pretty damn good. Like
look.
So we need to dial it in a little bit
more.
That is pretty good.
I don't have the other one. So I'm
trying to get this to line up where
Hey,
I should have put a mark on that
I didn't
cuz I cut it a little long. But look. So
if we square that up. If I square that
up. and do that.
I mean, the cut is pretty good right
there.
That is really good.
Why Why does everything have to be
level?
Well, because level's a control line,
kid.
I know.
Well, I mean, it doesn't have to be
level. In fact, making things level is
one of the hardest things in
construction.
Um, but if it's not level, you don't
have anything to square off of.
All right, kid.
Yep.
And one more time. This is Mark
here. Get back in there and just hold
that.
Hold that down right about there.
should have marked his ass, but I
didn't.
All right. Now,
well, yeah, dude. I'm telling you,
cutting one piece is probably the
hardest thing on planet Earth. Just
going to cut one more piece. Hey, how
about that?
There we go. All right, Kobe, look at
it.
All right, look here. Come bring your
ass over here. Look at that.
Look at that end. If that works, I got
to nail it. Does it line up?
What's it hitting on?
Okay, there's a piece of wood sticking
out right here.
Oh, that's that. No, it was already like
that. Ready?
How you looking right there?
Um,
pretty good.
But it's aligned, but
that's all right. Watch this. I'm going
to attack this
cuz look, that's wood. You just wood.
All right. I'm on my mark there now,
cuz that's that piece of wood.
You see now
hold it in place.
Here we go.
Ha. One more piece.
One more piece.
Oh my goodness gracious Christ almighty.
See that? One more.
Cut this one.
Huh?
Cut this.
Go for it. Last one. Woo boy.
Yes, sir. Now,
right.
All right. So, that isn't a bad cut, but
if you look, I got about an eighth of an
inch. So, I need to take a sheet off
there.
So, I need to cut about an eighth of an
inch off of that side.
Be long enough.
Barely long enough.
There we go.
All right.
So that that is actually on about a four
and I need to move it to a three. All
right. So I'm not putting this last one
on a three common.
Who knows what a three common is?
Come on now.
Ain't no carpenters out there. Like I
said, partner, if you're a carpenter,
we're not the same thing. I'm a partner.
Cut it this way.
Professional right there. See, do you
know why I never wear PPE, safety
goggles, masks, and everything? It's
because God protects idiots and fools.
And I know that. And you know, the the
the less protection I provide for
myself, the more he protects me. And
also just thinking, you know, like God
looks out for people who really really
try hard. Like if you had a whole bunch
of kids, but one of them was a little
slow with a lazy eye, but he tried
harder than the rest like me. Yeah, you
probably look out for him, too.
Hey, look at that. What you think? What
you think, kid? I think.
Hey, look at that mark. Now look. Hey,
LOOK AT THAT.
DUDE, THAT ACTUALLY looks pretty.
That's fire. Now hold it right
there. Now look at him. Now look, you
don't know this, but if you hold this in
the wrong spot and I mark it wrong, the
whole thing is ruined. Hold that right
there. And you Now look, you see right
there? Line it up. See those two lines?
The you can see the part that looks at
Hey, you can look at it and go, "This
looks like shit." You can do that, can't
you?
Mhm.
All right. Every day I do that with my
sister.
That is the most important part of
construction is being able to say
something looks terrible and and then
not do it because it looks like
Most people never get past this basic
premise.
That ladder
last cuts
ladders.
Cannot mess up the last cut, can we?
That's going to Oh, never mind.
Mike, one more square up, kid.
Right down.
Right down. Is that where it need to be?
Hey, go get your mama real quick. All
right.
She's going to like this.
This is a little love nest I'm building
with me and Alex as
[clears throat]
you know what I can't wait to do.
Well, I tell y'all, man. Let me nail
this up and then I tell you this crazy
I'm going to do.
Boom. Boom.
Boom. Okay.
Go ahead and nail it off.
That's it.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Come on now.
Get off my nuts. That looks fire.
Hell yeah.
Off my nuts.
Yes, sir.
Yeah. You know why I'm a hard guy to get
a hold of? Because I'd be
single-handedly running nine LLC's based
in two different countries in two
different languages and doing like
this with my own two hands while live
streaming all simultaneously. It's one
person, me, behind all these things. Uh
Alex has helped me. I have one assistant
in America, a number of people working
in Augusta, Georgia. And you know, I
have vendors in these towns, but it's
just me, bro. You getting me on the
phone?
Look at that. Let me step back.
That is fire.
Hell yeah.
That is gangster. What do you think?
Look.
I like that. I like
Hey, and that X is dead center, too.
And look. So, this is it, guys. This is
what I have built this far.
There's my teak bench.
Like I said, if I already showed you,
that whole thing's beveled. All this is
beveled. Uh, this is on an incline. You
can see my gat running up. I notched my
2 by six back there. I got a 2 by six
ledger right here holding the bench seat
up. And you can see I drove shims in
there to tweak that thing and lock it in
real well. And watch this. It's like a
80in bench.
Yeah. with only two 1x4s holding it up.
Strong as Um, all my siding, all
my lattice,
all that was done. Uh, like I said, all
this rabbited out. I mean, real tight
joints, too. Um, you can probably
appreciate these if you're a carpenter.
No nails in any of that. Uh, I got my
little bathroom area set up. When we
poured the slab, we got water running
down. We got to fix that.
I got this whole wall did. That was
hell. Then I fabricated this teak door
right
which is impervious to water. And hold
on. Check out the reveal.
Perfect. So,
uh, I don't know if I'm screen on it. I
do have screen. The mosquitoes here
aren't bad. Um,
what do you mean?
They're not bad. They way wor Hey, they
were worse than Georgia.
Yeah,
I don't No, they
This is where all the magic happens.
This is the wood we dried in the rain.
Yes, it worked. Um, this is fresh cut
cedar. I'm going to make tables out of
these. Uh, we made one big table.
right here already. This is guanoccaste.
It's a different type of wood. Really
light, really pretty. This is more
cedar. Uh building the beds and
everything out of this stuff. Um see
Alex doing the work here.
This does anybody know what this is?
Before I go,
see it spin.
This
is a trapiche.
This is a traditional sugar cane press.
Um, you take the sugar cane and you feed
it in there and it'll grab it and pull
it all the way through to here and all
the juice and everything will run out of
here. Um, and
there's the sugar cane. Come on now.
Come on now. Like what?
So, it's a wonderful place. I got a lot
of land. I'd say it's a little over 4
acres. Um, couple ectaradas.
And this is a massive, massive, massive
open space. There's group bathrooms with
five toilets and a shower over there.
And we have the tilapia ponds, lobster
ponds,
just I mean space galore
everywhere.
Um, as you can see, Alex is uh currently
trimming the star fruit. Um, yeah. But
guys, thank you. This is my first ever
live stream. Taught to y'all for an hour
and a half now. Um, I'll probably pop it
on and and just cut it up with you. And
uh if you ever want to get to me, man,
it's easier to get me on Instagram
because you can send messages. Uh I I
check them regularly, but a ton of them
and I'll audio message you back. Um this
is my little place in Costa Rica and uh
we're building this pretty soon.
We'll get the renewable energy center
open. Um Julian Brown will be here in a
week or so to visit me and so will Eric
Lungren, owner of Big Battery. I have a
lot of things to do here. Um but it all
begins with this renovation. If you want
to link with me, I'm pretty real. And if
you're real, too, we probably get along
great. If you're not, we won't get along
at all. So, you know, fair warning,
guys. Um, and in closing,
this is my backyard.
This is where I chose to build my home.
So wonderful.
And if you'd like to come here, all you
have to do is be cool. So, Josh, y'all
get at me, guys. Joe Fails signing out.
Holla.